华沙间谍
本字幕由3c区提供，最新电影下载，请上3c区(www.3cqu.com)
3c区(www.3cqu.com)- 第一时间发布最新最好看的电影
到边境还有多远
How far to the border?
不远了  我去年还来过这儿
Not far. Unless they changed it again
除非他们改道了
since I was here last.
在这从波兰到德国就像
Round here a man can rise from his bed in Poland,
一个人从起床到厨房一样近
go down to the kitchen and find himself in Germany.
你会好起来的 他们告诉我的
You're getting well, they tell me.
到时候去踢足球 怎么样
Playing football soon, eh?
希望如此吧 先生
I hope so, sir.
- 你去过那里几次?   - 是的
- You've been over there a few times?  - Yes.
你是不是看到了什么
Did you see something?
让他们这么生气地朝你开枪?
That made them angry enough to shoot you?
看到了带着铲子和机器的士兵
Soldiers. With shovels and machinery.
- 什么样的机器   - 搬运土的
- What kind of machinery?  - Moving the earth.
我们警告过Stefan
We warned Stefan not to
在他们加强边防之后不要去那边
go over after they strengthened the border.
- 有巡逻么?   - 每两个小时一次
- Are there patrols?  - Every two hours.
我们需要靠近点看
We should take a closer look.
两周后就是新月了
There's a new moon in two weeks.
我会去安排的
I'll arrange it.
和你弟弟击剑的男人是谁?
Who's the man fencing with your brother?
陆军中校
Colonel
Jean-Francois Mercier
Jean-Francois Mercier.
那位英勇的中校是做什么的
And what does the gallant Colonel do?
他是法国大使馆的军队随员
He's the Military Attache at the French Embassy.
他来华沙只有6个月
He's only been in Warsaw six months.
- 结婚了么?   - 或者丧偶?
- Married?  - Widowed?
别满怀期望了 Cecylia
Don't get your hopes up, Cecylia.
我早对他有意了
I already have my eye on him.
这个疤怎么来的
How did this happen?
刺刀伤的
A bayonet.
这个呢
And this?
被狙击手打中了
A sniper's bullet.
我还该看看哪里呢
Where else should I look?
医生说在我的左腿膝盖里
The doctor says there's still some shrapnel
还有一些弹片
in my left knee.
你这一代的大多数男人多少有些这样的伤疤
Most men of your generation have scars of some sort.
除非 像我丈夫那样
Unless, like my husband,
战争期间他们躲在家里 中饱私囊
they spent the war at home and got rich.
嗯 如果再来一次战争他会变得更富有
Well, if there's another he'll get even richer.
真是乱说话 确实
Crazy talk, surely
伯爵夫人!
Countess!
我...我才...我才想着...
I was... I was... I was beginning to think...
香槟  你个淘气鬼
Champagne! You wicked boy.
Uhl先生
Herr Uhl.
- 你脸色不太好   - 睡太少了
- You look pale.  - Too little sleep.
你带了什么来?
What have you got for me?
第一批新坦克炮塔的图纸
The first diagrams for the new tank turret.
有什么不同?
What's different?
是一样的
It's the same.
但是现在这些护板都是...
But now the plates are to be...
你的啤酒
One beer for you.
这些护板都经过表面硬化
The plates are to be face-hardened.
这意味着是渗碳处理过的
That means carbon cementation.
非常昂贵 但是强度得以大幅增加
Very expensive but the strength is greatly increased.
下次我们想要看到
Next time we'd like to see the formula
表面硬化工艺的配方
for the face-hardening process.
下次? 我不确定
Next time? I'm not sure
我可以在...
I'll be able...
就11月15号
15th November.
麻烦太多了
There are many problems.
这种工作总会有麻烦的
There are always problems in this sort of work
但是酬劳优越
but you can use the money.
伯爵夫人的品位很高
The Countess has expensive tastes.
这是一千兹罗提
A thousand zlotys.
波兰的货币单位
你走吧  好让我喝完我的啤酒
Go on. Let me finish my beer.
早上好  早上好
Morning. Morning.
大使馆正在为我们雷诺的员工
The embassy are holding a dinner for our people
Renault：雷诺公司 法国车辆制造商
举行晚宴
from Renault.
他们来这出售他们的坦克的
They're coming here to sell their tanks.
不会这么简单的
That won't be easy.
我收集到的情报显示
The information I've received suggests to me that the
德国人正在准备一场不同的战斗
Germans are preparing for a different kind of combat.
又一个你关于
Is this another one of
战争可能性的悲观预言么?
your gloomy predictions about the likelihood of war?
迹象很明确
There are certain indications.
如果是这样 那么试着用你的
If so, try to use your
影响力来劝说波兰人买法国货吧
influence to persuade the Poles to buy French.
这场晚宴 他们把我们配成一对了
They've paired us off for this dinner,
但是我有点感冒
but I'm fighting a cold,
Jean-Francois
Jean-Francois.
如果你把感冒传染给我
If you give it to me
我们都可以托病不去了
we could both be excused.
你无法这么轻易的摆脱
You're not getting out of it that easily.
但是 我给你找了个人替代我
But I've found you a substitute.
Anna Skarbek
Anna Skarbek,
一个讨人喜欢的女孩
a delightful girl.
是国际联盟的律师
A lawyer with the League of Nations.
晚宴过后还有舞会
And afterwards there will be dancing.
我会尽量不去踩到她的脚趾
I'll try not to step on her toes.
我找Skarbek女士
I'm looking for Madame Skarbek.
她快准备好了  请进吧
She's almost ready. Come in.
Anna 你的将军来了
Anna, your general is here!
这就来
Coming!
不能算是将军  是陆军中校
Not quite a general. Lieutenant colonel.
在人看来也是一位勇士
A brave one too by the look of it.
不过是个幸运的人  我还活着
A lucky one. I'm alive.
我也是  我是幸存下来的该死的布尔什维克
As am I. I survived bloody Bolsheviks.
我是Maxim
I'm Maxim.
我是Jean-Francois
Jean-Francois.
- 这件怎么样   - 光彩夺目
- Will this do?  - Splendidly.
我不怎么参加正式的晚会的
I don't go to many formal dinners.
非常感谢您在如此短的时间内做到这一点
It's very kind of you to do this at such short notice.
Dupin夫人对每个人都那么好
Madame Dupin does favours for everyone
我怎么能拒绝呢
so how could I refuse?
早点送她回来 好么
Don't bring her back too late, eh?
别喝太多了
Don't drink too much.
你一直住在华沙吗
Have you always lived in Warsaw?
不 我在这里才不过一年
No, I've been here just over a year.
我的工作需要长久奔波
My work means I travel a lot.
那么你的家在哪里
So where's home?
我出生在巴黎 有波兰血统
I'm Parisian by birth, Polish by heritage.
所以巴黎是我们的共同点
So we have Paris in common.
以防我们无话可谈么?
In case we run out of conversation?
我确信我们不会那样的 Skarbek女士
I'm sure we won't do that, Madame Skarbek.
请叫我Anna小姐 总之目前这样称呼就好
Anna, please. And it's Mam'selle. For a while anyhow.
晚上好
Good evening.
Evening.
Anna 你在这里  不好意思
Anna, here you are. Would you excuse us?
我认为他们叫我们去用餐了
I think they want us at table.
很高兴跟你谈话 Blanc先生
So nice talking to you, Monsieur Blanc.
抱歉 你是被纠缠了么
I'm sorry, were you trapped?
不是那样 他是一位专门研究履带的工程师
Not at all. He's an engineer specialising in treads.
他很迷人
Fascinating.
Mercier 你这家伙
Mercier, you dog!
你都把这位美丽的女士藏在哪了
Where have you been hiding this beautiful lady?
Anna Skarbek
Anna Skarbek,
这位是Antoni Pakulski上校
this is Colonel Antoni Pakulski.
答非所问
That does not answer my question.
我们一小时前才认识
We met an hour ago.
真的么   我们是老朋友了
Really? We are old friends.
在他赢得这个波兰军事十字勋章的时候
I was with him when he won this.
我就在他身边
The Virtuti Militari.
Virtuti Militari：1939年9月2日，第18波美拉尼亚枪骑兵团被该作战集群司令史坦斯洛夫・戈尔斯摩特-斯克丁尼基（Stanislaw Grzmot-Skotnicki）用他自己的波兰军事十字勋章（Virtuti Militari）授勋奖励该单位的英勇表现。
一个法国人是如何赢得波兰勋章的?
How did a Frenchman win a Polish medal?
1920年时
He was attached
他在我骑兵中队属下时候获得的
to my cavalry squadron in 1920.
我们一起击退了苏联红军
We fought off the Red Army together.
就你们两个?
Just the two of you?
可能还有其他人 我不记得了
There may have been others, I don't recall.
稍后请赏光共舞一曲吧
Promise me a dance later.
跳舞?
Dancing?
是的  所以我本该强烈反对那六道菜的
Yes. So I would advise against all six courses.
你是不是经常如此?
Is this something you do often?
不幸的是 差不多每晚都这样
Unhappily, almost every night.
我浅酌红酒 品尝食物
I sip the wine, taste the food,
发现每个人都这么迷人
find everyone fascinating.
外交的一句好格言
A good motto for diplomacy.
这是拯救世界的方法之一
It's one way to save the world.
你跳的很好 Jean-Francois
You dance well, Jean-Francois.
我妻子过去喜爱跳舞
My wife loved to dance.
发生了什么
What happened?
肺痨  三年前的事了
Consumption. Three years ago.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你一定很想念你的妻子吧
You must miss your wife.
是的  她曾让这样的夜晚不那么难熬
I do. She made these evenings tolerable.
现在有你
As have you.
这倒是意外之喜
It's been an unexpected pleasure.
我已经了解很多关于这坦克的事情了
And I've learned so much about this tank.
我在担心它的装备
I worry about the armament
一个37毫米加农炮和仅仅一挺机枪吗?
a 37-millimetre cannon with only one machine gun?
你已经跟Pakulski上校谈过话了
You've been talking to Colonel Pakulski.
他认为波兰买不起
He thinks it's not much of a machine for Poland's money.
一旦德国的坦克碾压过境
Better than nothing if German tanks roll
有军备总比赤手空拳好
across the border.
要是德国人这么做了
But if they do, surely
英勇的法国人会施以援手么
the gallant French will rush to our rescue?
可否邀请您的舞伴?   - 可以
May I?  - Of course.
哦 这不是什么好主意
Oh, not a good idea
在喝过苏格兰威士忌
after Scotch,
红葡萄酒和白兰地后
claret and slivovitz.
根本不是什么好主意
Not a good idea at all.
你无所不知 Antoni
You know everything, Antoni.
跟她生活在一起的那个俄罗斯人是什么来历?
What's the story with this Russian she lives with?
Maxim Mostov 白俄罗斯人
Maxim Mostov. White Russian.
自从他离开家乡后他云游四方
He's lived in many places since he left his homeland.
他是一个政治记者
He makes a living as a political journalist.
主要攻击斯大林的
Mostly attacking Stalin.
话多 喝的更多
Talks too much and drinks even more.
为什么她和他在一起?
Why is she with him?
谁懂女人呢?
Who knows with women?
他们在一起多久了
How long have they been together?
够长了 你就在想这些么
Long enough, is that what you are thinking?
小心为妙啊 我的朋友
Careful, my friend.
已经3点半了
It's 3.30.
我答应过不能太晚带你回家的
I was told not to bring you back too late.
Max估计已经睡了  不必费心送我上楼了
Max will be asleep. Don't bother to see me upstairs.
还有 感谢你 这是个难忘的夜晚
And thank you for a memorable evening.
来杯咖啡
Coffee, please.
给这位女士来杯巧克力
And another chocolate for Madame.
总是这么准时啊 上校
Always so punctual, Colonel.
你跟Uhl先生约会准时么
Were you on time for your rendezvous with Herr Uhl?
伯爵夫人总是姗姗来迟
For him the Countess is always late.
她有时不太随和 我相当喜欢她
She can be difficult at times. I rather like her.
当然 他认为她是身无分文的
Of course he thinks she's penniless.
他又借给她一些你的钱了
He loaned her some more of your money.
你想把钱收回来么
Do you want it back?
留着吧 Olga
No keep it, Olga.
我们已经按惯例为你存了款
We've made your usual deposit.
我们对你所做的一切感激在心
We're appreciative of what you do.
也许我生来就是个间谍
Perhaps I was born to be a spy.
我们得适应我们所处的时代
We adapt to the times we live in.
法国有句俗语
There's a French saying,
"神随意栽种 人自求繁荣"
"Wherever God has planted you, you must know how to flower."
这对之前的事情无疑是种促进
It's certainly an improvement on what came before.
你是怎么找到Uhl先生的?
How did you find Herr Uhl?
每次华沙之行都是他生命的极乐时刻
His trips to Warsaw are the high points of his life.
另外他工作在外 是个顾家的好男人
Otherwise he labours away, the good family man.
他下个月会再来
He'll be back next month.
尽管有些不情愿
Though he showed some reluctance.
哦 他会回来的
Oh, he'll come.
他甚至可能已经爱上伯爵夫人了
He may even be in love with the Countess.
我是不是演过头了
Am I overplaying my part?
我的围巾 我落车上了
My scarf, I left it.
- 该死 这些人   - 请让我进去
- Fuck these people.  - Please!
没到时候
Not yet.
就现在
Now.
他们在外面还有巡逻
They still have patrols out there.
下一轮巡逻过来是在9点25分
The next one comes through at 9.35.
他们总是那么准时么?   - 分毫不差
They're always prompt?  - Like a clock.
- 带着狗?   - 一直是
- Dogs?  - Always.
你确定要这么做 中校?
Sure you want to do this, Colonel?
要是他们看到你 会当场开枪的
If they see you they'll shoot on sight.
如果我们不出来 在车上动点手脚就没事
If we don't show up, do something with the car.
还好吧?   - 我没事
All right?  - I'm OK.
这是什么
What is it?
是一个坦克的陷阱
It's a tank trap.
为什么他们要覆盖他们的坦克陷阱?
Why are they covering their tank traps?
这没道理啊
That doesn't make sense.
往光源处打
Go for the light.
走 走 快走 快 快!
Go, go, go, go, go!
我昨晚在找你
I looked for you last night.
你是不是忘记了王子和我要举办一个晚会?
Did you forget the Prince and I were holding a soiree?
昨晚实难抽身 公主
It was impossible to get away, Princess.
文书工作堆积如山
Paperwork. Reams of it.
嗯 这又是什么 纸划伤的?
Hmm, and what's this, a paper cut?
我读了你的报告
I read your report.
- 看上去真是千钧一发   - 我很幸运
- A near miss by the sound of it.  - I was fortunate.
如果被抓了呢  要是你射到某人了呢?
What if you were caught? Or you'd shot someone?
天哪 那我们要如何解释?
Christ, how would we explain that?
我并没有那样做 也没有人那么做
I wasn't. And no-one was.
巴黎将会持怀疑态度的
Paris will take a dim view of this.
你做什么 你想试着证明什么
What are you, what are you trying to prove?
我想我已经解释明白了
I thought I made that clear.
他们覆盖了陷阱
They're covering traps
这样他们自己的坦克便不会受到阻碍
so their own tanks won't be impeded.
你的意思是如果他们入侵
If they invade, you mean.
希特勒铁了心要发动战争
Hitler is intent on war,
唯一的问题是
it's only a question of
他会先攻打谁
who he picks a fight with first.
亲爱的中校  日子过的如何
Dear Colonel! How has life been treating you?
非常好 Rozen女士  你们二位呢
Very well, Madame Rozen. And yourselves?
本应更好些 但是我们没法抱怨什么
Could be better, but we can't complain.
他是你的朋友么
Is he a friend of yours?
不算是  一个同胞 但是是个流亡者
Not exactly. A compatriot, but an emigre.
一些人放弃了我们 是多么的悲哀啊
Sad how some people abandon us.
一部分是最聪明的人啊
Some of the brightest.
不是每个人都想建设社会主义的 亲爱的
Not everyone wants to build socialism, my love.
嗯 在我们的家乡
Well, it isn't an easy life,
生活着实不易 为什么不承认呢
where we come from, why not admit it?
但是 中校
But, Colonel,
比起我们之前的生活好多了
better than what we had before.
失陪了
Excuse me.
Anna
Anna.
我知道你觉得这类场合很无聊
I know you find these occasions boring
但是 我已经开始乐在其中了
but I'm beginning to enjoy them.
或者是享受香槟?
Or is it the champagne?
香槟确实有帮助
The champagne helps.
所以你认识Rozen夫妇
So you know the Rozens.
每个人都知道他们
Everyone knows them.
他们试图拉拢你吗
Do they try to recruit you?
Max说俄罗斯大使馆的
Max says everyone at the
每一个人都是间谍 即使看门人也是
Russian Embassy is a spy, even the janitor.
嗯 Malka时常想给我煮些罗宋汤
Well, Malka offers to cook me borscht from time to time.
他们当然鄙视Max 因为他的文章
They despise Max of course, because of what he writes.
距离俄罗斯进行试验时日不多了...
It's not so far from the Russian experiment...
我最好把他带回家
I'd better get him home.
他让美国大使走投无路了
He's cornered the American Ambassador.
你们这些美国人听到"社会主义"
You Americans go weak at the knees
腿都软了
when you hear the word "Socialism"
你还能叫它什么
But what else can you call it?
为什么她和这个俄罗斯人在一起
Why is she with this Russian?
你讨厌俄罗斯人就跟
You hate Russians
讨厌德国人一样吧 Marek?
as much as Germans, Marek?
别无选择  一个在东边 一个在西边
Nothing to choose. One to the east, one to the west.
两边都希望像敲核桃一样侵入波兰
Both waiting to crush Poland like a walnut.
你想去哪儿 头儿?
You wish to go on somewhere, boss?
餐馆还是夜总会?
Restaurant? Nightclub?
不 我想回家 把这该死的领结脱下来
No, I want to go home and get this bloody collar off.
伯爵夫人 自从你向我介绍
Countess, since you introduced
那个法国人 我的生命就发生了改变
me to the Frenchman, my life has changed.
当然 这使得我们关系更加密切
It has brought us closer, of course,
但是 我陷入了一个
but, I am caught up in a
危险的游戏 这是个危险的时代
dangerous game and these are dangerous times.
你不希望再见到我了么
You don't wish to see me again?
哦 不 当然不是喽
Oh, no, of course I do.
你知道我对你的感情
You know how I feel about you.
但是也许我们不得不考虑一下我们的将来
But perhaps we have to think of our future.
在一起么?
Together?
为什么不呢
Why not?
Edvard 我已经逃离了故土
Edvard, I have already fled the country of my birth.
我已经不知道哪里会安全了
I don't know where is safe any more.
和我在一起就安全了
Safe would be with me.
都在这了
Here it is.
最后的设计图应该在下个月就会完成
The final blueprints should be complete by next month.
那么我们下次就到那时候见
Then that's when we'll meet next.
啊 这恐怕很难
Ah, that's difficult.
8号我和其他两名工程师
On the eighth me and two other engineers,
我们必须去施兰贝格的黑森林
we have to go to Schramberg in the Black Forest.
施兰贝格：德国巴登-符腾堡州的一个市镇
去干什么
What for?
去观察坦克演习
To observe tank exercises.
我们被要求提供建议
We're being asked for our recommendations.
演习?  你指的是军事演习?
Exercises? You mean manoeuvres?
军事演戏 是的 我是这么猜想的
Manoeuvres, yes, I suppose so.
坦克不会进森林的吧 Uhl先生
Tanks don't go in forests, Herr Uhl.
森林里有树
There are trees in forests.
我不是军人
I'm not a military man.
我怎么知道他们在做些什么?
How would I know what they're up to?
我们一周后见
Let's meet a week later.
我会的  但是从此我们交易结束
I will do that. But then it ends.
上次 盖世太保在边界上
Last time, the Gestapo were at the border.
我不得不躲开他们
I had to elude them,
从铁轨上爬下来
scramble down the tracks
然后乘出租车去下一站
and take a taxi to the next station.
你在怕什么
What were you frightened of?
如果他们问我 我在华沙做什么
What if they asked me what I was doing in Warsaw?!
告诉他们你去和一位女士幽会
Tell them you were seeing a lady.
通奸还不算犯罪
Adultery is not yet a crime.
Uhl先生?
Herr Uhl?
是的?
Yes?
我是Renata  伯爵夫人的侄女
I'm Renata. The Countess's niece.
她想让我在你去车站前找到你
She wanted me to catch you before you went to the station.
她是不是身体不太好   - 不 不 不
Is she unwell?  - No, no, no.
她说有重要的事要告诉你
She says it's important that she tells you something
在你上火车前
before you catch your train.
- 那女孩是谁   - 什么女孩
- Who is the girl? - What girl?
见过你线人的金发女郎
The blonde who met your man.
他跟她走了
He went off with her.
不好责怪他 她长的很漂亮
Hard to blame him, she was very pretty.
她是妓女么
Was she a prostitute?
为什么在他跟他的伯爵夫人共度春宵后
Why would he want a tart
还想要一个妓女?
after a night with his Countess?
他们朝哪个方向去了?
Which way did they go?
朝Muranow区
Towards Muranow.
我们去跟着他们
Let's get after them.
伯爵夫人住这儿?
The Countess lives here?
她告诉我没有你的帮助
She tells me without your help
事情会变得更糟糕
it would be somewhere worse.
我觉得不妙  有些不对劲
I don't like this. Something isn't right.
发生了什么
What's going on?
这个人病了
The man is sick.
他没病 他被麻醉了
He's not sick, he's drugged.
是三氯甲烷
It's chloroform.
他死了么
Is he dead?
还有脉搏
There's a pulse.
很微弱 但是还有
It's faint, but it's there.
公共场合的绑架 街头斗殴
An abduction in public, brawling in the streets!
难道我们希望早报上出现这些么?
Are we to look forward to this in the morning papers?
不 Jourdain
No, Jourdain,
我来打几个电话掩盖掉这件事
I made some calls and put the lid on it.
这个人是谁
Who was this man?
一个线人
A contact.
你是说他是间谍 他还活着么?
You mean a spy. Will he live?
是的 但是他不能回德国了
Yes, but he can't go back to Germany.
我会向他保证
I'd like to assure him
我们能帮助他重新安置下来
that we can help with some kind of relocation.
基于什么理由
On what grounds?
他应得的
He's earned it.
并且我打算继续调查他告诉我的事儿
And I intend to follow up on what he told me.
记住 中校
Try to remember, Colonel,
你在这里的职责是机密
that your function here is covert,
我们希望你办事
which means we want to hear as little as possible
越低调越好
about what you get up to.
你看起来可不怎么样 你还好吧
You don't look well. Are you all right?
有点头痛
A slight headache.
嗯 我觉得你是在装样子
Well, I presume you're in some sort of disguise.
如果没有 那么我就把我裁缝的名字告诉你
If not, let me get you the name of my tailor.
我一直向往南非
I was hoping for South Africa.
我已经申请了签证
I already applied for a visa.
这可不明智
That was unwise.
一旦被盖世太保发现
If the Gestapo found out, that might explain why
他们逮捕你时就有了个好理由
they tried to snatch you when they did.
但你能把我带到那  是吧
But you can get me there? Yes?
一个全新的生活
A new life?
不  德国特工会等着你的
No. German agents will be waiting for you.
你得去法国的某处
It has to be somewhere French.
或许是加拿大
Canada perhaps.
加拿大
Canada?
伯爵夫人有可能在那儿与我碰头吗
Would it be possible for the Countess to join me there?
Uhl先生
Herr Uhl...
她不是伯爵夫人
she's not a Countess.
她也不曾爱过你
Nor was she ever in love with you.
他清醒了 是不
He's awake, then?
认清了他生活的事实
Awake to the facts of life.
官方报道 他死于因窒息
Officially, he died of cardiac arrest,
引起的心脏骤停
brought on by asphyxiation.
这样应该可以摆脱德国方面的追踪
That should throw the Germans off the trail.
十分感谢
Thank you.
你注意过这儿的护士有多年轻么
Have you noticed how young these nurses are?
或者只是说我们在渐渐老去
Or is it just that we're getting older?
恐怕是吧 Antoni
I'm afraid so, Antoni.
我刚收到了一封来自华沙的电报
Uhl死了
你不仅搞砸了他的绑架
你该死的还杀了他
白痴!
我简直不能相信
Sturmbannfuehrer先生
去看看他的遗孀
以表我们的慰问和哀思?
不 你这蠢货
去把房子搜个底朝天
你在藏什么呢 Zoller
难不成你是犹太人
一些拼图被弄丢了
Some pieces are missing.
我找不到这块 哪儿都找不到
I can't find this one, I can't find it anywhere.
你睡眠好点儿了吗
Are you sleeping better?
并不怎么样
Not really.
他们待我并不是很好 你知道的
They don't treat me very well here, you know.
那些年轻人似乎忘记了
The younger ones seem to forget that
这儿曾经是我的房子
this was my house once.
如果我能的话 他们估计全都要被解雇了
And if it was, I'd dismiss most of them.
华沙怎么样
How's Warsaw?
阴冷潮湿
Cold and wet.
遇到了真命天子么?
Is there a man in your life?
我给你说过Max
I've told you about Max.
噢 他还蒙受你青眼?
Oh, he's still in the picture?
是啊 母亲
Yes, Mother.
嗯 我搞不懂你为什么
Well, I wonder why
从来不带他来见我
it is you've never brought him here to see me.
因为你不喜欢俄罗斯人
Because you don't like Russians.
呃 这是事实  还有德国人
Well, that's true. Or Germans.
如果我们还呆在巴黎的话
If we'd stayed in Paris,
现在你已经和某个法国人结婚了
you'd be married to a Frenchman by now.
我最近见着了一个
I met one recently.
他似乎被我迷住了
He seemed quite taken with me.
他有土地么
Does he have land?
不清楚
I've no idea.
嗯 他们经常装作
Well, they often pretend
自己封邑无数 等到最后却是一贫如洗
they do and then they turn out to be penniless.
我是说 你的俄罗斯小伙没有钱
I mean, your Russian doesn't have money.
我需要一块带些绿色的蓝天拼图
I need a piece of blue sky with a little bit of green.
德国人在试图抓捕Uhl先生
The Germans tried to snatch Herr Uhl.
也许是盖世太保在盯着他
It could be the Gestapo is onto him.
他们可能已经知道你了
They may know about you.
如果他们知道 他们会去寻找
If so, they'll be looking
Potocki伯爵夫人
for the Countess Potocki,
而不是Olga Musser
not Olga Musser.
即便如此 我们也要做到未雨绸缪
Even so, we should take precautions.
于是派来一个保镖
A bodyguard, perhaps?
高挑英俊又对某一年龄段的女性
Tall and handsome with a soft spot
情有独钟
for women of a certain age?
Olga 请认真对待这事
Olga, please treat this seriously.
收拾收拾东西 搬去这家旅店里住几天
Take some things, move to this hotel for a few days.
就在Sienna大街
It's on Sienna Street,
离Cleo咖啡厅不远
not far from the Cafe Cleo.
预约时我用了你的真实姓名
The reservation's under your real name.
那么不再是伯爵夫人了
So no more Countess?
我会怀念她的
I shall miss her.
我最近没有见到你 Lapp博士
I haven't seen you of late, Dr Lapp.
你去旅行了
Have you been travelling?
柏林 出席我公司的销售会议
Berlin, for my company's sales conference.
在那期间
While I was there,
温莎公爵和夫人去拜访了希特勒先生
the Duke and Duchess of Windsor visited Herr Hitler.
微笑 握手 再挥手
Smiles, handshakes and waves.
英国人也被他蛊惑了不成
Are the English falling under his spell too?
你不赞同现政权
You don't approve of the present regime?
古老欧洲的文化 礼仪 稳定
The culture of old Europe, civility, stability...
对德国来说可不是个坏事
was not such a bad thing for Germany.
我们德国人也许并不像你想的
Some of us Germans may not be
那样像法国的敌人
so much the enemy of France as you might think.
抱歉 您刚才说什么
Sorry, you were saying?
没关系
Don't worry.
美丽的女士同样总会吸引我的目光
A beautiful woman always catches my eye too.
你认识她
You know her?
我们最近见过一面  我 我应该向她问声好
We met recently. I... I should say hello.
当然  若一切顺利 我想我该说再见了
Of course. And if it goes well, I will say goodbye.
见到你总是很愉快 Lapp博士
Always good to see you, Dr Lapp.
我能否与你同桌?  还是说你在等Max
May I? Or is Max joining you?
不  Max正在忙着赶文章
No. Max is finishing an article.
我来这儿是为了避雨
I came here to get out of the rain.
我去了电影院
I've been to the cinema.
去看什么
To see what?
Laurel和Hardy的片子
Laurel and Hardy.
大闹玩具城
Babes In Toyland.
我需要一些欢笑
I needed a laugh.
你为什么不开心
What made you sad?
我母亲的情况不是很好
My mother is unwell.
自我父亲去世起她就没有好起来过了
She's never been quite right since my father died.
她怀念过去的奢华时光
She misses the grand old days.
她接受不了自己有一个工作的女儿
She can't believe she has a daughter who works.
所以你的童年生活优越?
So you had a privileged childhood?
和你比就不算什么了
Not compared to you.
这戒指难道不代表着你是一位贵族
Doesn't this ring mean you're nobility?
噢 只是个卑微的骑士罢了
Oh, just a lowly chevalier.
效忠于国王的骑士
A knight in service to the king -
在法国还有国王的时候
when France had a king.
不过  仍是我唯一认识的贵族
Still... the only one I've ever known.
你一直在检查我
You've been checking up on me.
是的 我回来了 亲爱的们
Yes, I'm home, my darlings.
这些信件 大多都是账单
These letters - bills mostly -
全是寄给Olga Musser的
are addressed to Olga Musser.
那么是谁出主意让你变成一个伯爵夫人
So whose idea was it to make you a Countess?
我简直不能相信现在有多晚了
I can't believe how late it is.
Max会伤心吗
Will Max be upset?
如果知道你带我去了个那么棒的餐厅
He might be upset that
他一定会沮丧的
you took me to such a fine restaurant
并且你还点了那么好的红酒
and that you ordered some very good wine.
人生得意须尽欢 莫使金樽空对月
Life's too short to drink bad wine.
谢谢了
Thank you.
谢谢你让我重拾笑容
And thank you for making me smile.
什么时候我才能再见到你
When can I see you again?
也许不如不见的好
Maybe it's better if we don't.
我认为 欢愉不过再相逢
I think it might be better if we do.
晚安 Jean-Francois
Good night, Jean-Francois.
写完了么
Did you finish it?
没什么价值
For what it's worth.
都是些废话  我没机会再写
Chit-chat. I don't have the
正儿八经的东西了
chance to write anything serious any more.
就算我可以 我还有什么好写的呢
And if I did, would I have anything to say?
你是一个很棒的作家 Max
You're a brilliant writer, Max.
只是要静候良机
Just bide your time.
也许我应该去趟英格兰
Maybe I should go to England.
他们可能会在公园里给我一个街头演说台
They might give me a soapbox in the park.
每逢周六我就可以愤怒地反对斯大林
On Saturdays, I can rage against Stalin.
到了周日是希特勒
On Sundays, Hitler.
谁送你回家的  我在窗户外见着你了
Who brought you home? I saw you from the window.
Mercier中校
Colonel Mercier.
我该嫉妒这个中校么
Should I be jealous of the Colonel?
去睡觉 你这老家伙  我给你弄些热牛奶
Get to bed, you old bear. I'll bring you some hot milk.
谁发现的她
Who found her?
一个邻居
A neighbour.
她有好几天没看见她了
She hadn't seen her for a couple of days,
猫也吵吵闹闹的
and the cat was making a racket.
她怎么死的
How did she die?
被勒死的
Strangled.
为什么警方让你来处理
Why did the police bring you into this?
另一个邻居听到有人离开的声音
Another neighbour heard men
并且认为他们讲的是德语
leaving and thought they were German voices.
这样一来就是一场国内安全事故
That makes this an internal security matter.
我知道她是你的线人之一
I know she was one of your contacts,
Jean-Francois
Jean-Francois.
这就是我找你的原因
That's why I called you.
死的可真惨
What a horrible way to die.
可怜的Olga
Poor bloody Olga.
她被折磨过么
Was she tortured?
我猜她很快就交待了
I imagine she told them
他们想知道的一切
what they wanted to know fairly quickly.
这是我们工作的可怕一面 Antoni
This is the terrible part of what we do, Antoni.
雇佣某人 获取他们信任 任用他们
Recruit someone, gain their trust, use them,
然后在某一天
and then one day...
我们仅仅是战士的时候就简单多了
It was easier when we were simply soldiers.
嗯
Hmm.
黑就是黑 白就是白  没有灰色地带
Black and white. Now everything is grey.
阴影  秘密
Shadows. Secrets.
你有我的资料吗
Do you have a file on me?
有一小份  你肯定有更多我的资料
A thin one. I'm sure you have more on me.
我不揣冒昧地假设是Marek报告给你的
I presume Marek reports to you.
他是你身后的好人
He's a good man to have at your back.
现在你陷入险境了
You're in danger yourself now.
我想巴黎已经为你这次的德国行动
I think Paris has sent everything for your
准备好了一切
jaunt into Germany.
地图 天气预报
Maps, weather reports.
噢 你之前用过这其中任何一样么
Oh, have you used one of these before?
没有
No.
换装的地点就在这儿的某处
The directions for reloading are somewhere here.
相机里有一个胶卷 背包里还有十个
There's a film in the camera and ten more in the knapsack.
你将会在巴塞尔得到一辆车
You'll pick up a car in Basel
然后开着它越过边境
and drive over the border.
你是Albert Ducasse
You're Albert Ducasse,
瑞士一城市
来自洛桑市
from Lausanne.
巴黎方面希望你在这儿留下自己的护照
Paris wants you to leave your own passport here.
别被抓住 因为
Do try not to be caught, because,
从技术层面上说 你是一名间谍
technically speaking, you're a spy.
在这种情况下会遭枪杀的
And in that situation could be shot.
您此行的目的是什么 Ducasse先生
What is the purpose of your visit, Herr Ducasse?
去弗莱堡参加一场婚礼
A wedding in Freiburg.
起来
我只是一个鸟类学家
到这儿来
带上你的相机
过来
往前走
这一幕明确地显示了
The post made the motorcycle
摩托车确实和坦克一样宽
exactly the same width as a tank.
我看见他们测量了
I watched them measure it.
这个军官在试着证实他们
The officer was trying to prove that
如果坦克有办法穿过树林
if that could find a way
那么一个装甲师也可以
through the trees, then so could a Panzer division.
你被发现了
You were discovered?
很遗憾  但我把他处理了
Regrettably. I took care of him.
你杀了他
You killed him?
他还不到18岁
He was no more than 18 years old.
我堵了他的嘴 用步枪背带把他绑了起来
I gagged him and tied him up with his rifle strap.
你变得优柔寡断了 Mercier
You're getting soft, Mercier.
我们并不在战场上 Lessard上校
We're not at war, Colonel Lessard.
现在还没有
Not yet.
你上份报告提到了
Your previous report
波兰边境的坦克陷阱
concerned tank traps on the Polish border.
就像你已经注意到的 被填平了
Which as you may have noticed, is flat.
波兰大草原是为坦克入侵
Polish steppes are
而量身定做的完美战场
tailor-made for tank invasion.
所以他们为什么要在一个森林里进行军演
So why are they holding manoeuvres in a forest?
也许波兰并不是他们的唯一目标
Possibly Poland is not their sole objective.
你认为他们会入侵我们?
You think they'll invade us?
他们可能会从比利时横穿阿登高地
They could come through the Ardennes from Belgium.
他们会撞进马其诺防线
They'd run into the Maginot Line forts -
那无异于是自杀
it would be suicide.
我认为那就是他们需要在
I believe that's what they were
在施兰贝格进行完善的东西
trying to refine in Schramberg.
什么风把你吹来了
What information took you there?
我的线人 Uhl先生
My contact, Herr Uhl.
噢 是的
Oh, yes,
那个我们得花点代价负责重新安置的人
the man we're now obliged to relocate, at some expense.
当然 活在魁北克可比
Of course, living in Quebec is somewhat preferable
死在华沙好多了 就像你的女特工一样
to being dead in Warsaw, the fate of your woman agent.
你其他一些试图越过边境的
Your other little foray over the border
小尝试都以枪声结束了
ended in gunshots.
也许披风和匕首并不是你的强项
Perhaps cloak and dagger isn't your strong suit,
Mercier
Mercier.
你愿意接受一项新任务么
Would you prefer a new assignment?
不 上校  我选择留在波兰
No, Colonel. My preference is to remain in Poland.
这由Beauvilliers将军决定
That is up to General Beauvilliers.
他想与你共进午餐
He wants to have lunch with you.
噢 别担心Lessard
Oh, don't worry about Lessard.
我要你人在华沙
I want you in Warsaw
安抚波兰民心 告诉他们如果最糟的情况发生
to reassure the Poles that we'll come to their aid
我们会出手援助
if the worst happens.
你确定政客们会履行条约么
Are you sure the politicians will honour the treaties?
不
No...
看上帝的份上 别告诉他们
but for God's sake, don't tell them that.
达拉第还有那个英国白痴张伯伦都很乐意
Daladier and that English moron Chamberlain are keen
英法绥靖政策执行者
与希特勒达成协议
to strike a deal with Hitler.
对于他们而言
To them,
捷克人和波兰人完全是可有可无的
the Czechs and the Poles are entirely dispensable.
这是Anglea Hope女士
That's Lady Angela Hope,
巴黎社交界的支柱
a pillar of Parisian society.
将军  一切可合您口味
General! Everything to your satisfaction?
这些牡蛎和平时一样美味 先生
The oysters were excellent as usual, Papa.
能为您提供喜爱的食物是我们的荣幸
So glad we could offer your favourite table.
就要上酸菜了
The choucroute is on its way.
配着两杯你最好的比尔森啤酒
With two glasses of your best Pilsner.
为何这桌如此特别
Why is this table so special?
一名保加利亚的服务总管在这里被暗杀了
A Bulgarian head waiter was assassinated here.
子弹横飞
Bullets all over the place.
所有的镜子都是重装的 除了这个
All the mirrors were replaced except this one.
真是不错的故事
It's a good story.
个人而言 我就是为这点谣传来的
Personally, I come here for the gossip.
所以
So...
波兰
Poland.
他们倾尽所能地去购置武器
They're doing their best to buy weapons,
同时遭受着经济危机的凌虐
though the Depression crippled their economy.
并且德军也在制造坦克
And the Germans are building tanks...
越来越多的坦克 并且正在调试已有的那些
and more tanks and modifying the ones they've got.
入侵计划
Invasion plans.
在这灰色事务中闪着不少宝石
There are many gems in this murky business,
各种祖母绿和红宝石
all sorts of emeralds and rubies.
发现这些计划
But find those plans,
你就可以得到皇冠上的明珠
and you have the jewel in the crown.
并且他们只来自一座矿藏 将军 IN6
And they come from only one mine, General IN6.
德国总参谋部的策划组
The planning section of the German General Staff.
难以置信 你会这么说么
Impossible, would you say?
也许不是  只是在正确的时间遇上对的人
Perhaps not. The right person, the right moment.
Lapp博士这个名字对你来说意味着什么吗
Does the name Dr Lapp mean anything to you?
不  他是谁
No. Who is he?
他声称代表一家德国制药公司
He claims to represent a German pharmaceutical company,
但我怀疑他连一片药都没卖过
but I doubt he's ever sold a pill.
他发表评论
He makes remarks.
做暗示
Hints.
仿佛他想做的比小叙一会儿要深入的多
As if he wants to make more than small talk.
我会替你留意他的
I'll check him for you.
噢 是的 这看起来很不错
Oh, yes, this looks excellent.
我十分确定我们应该这么做
I definitely think we should do that.
开放参观
Open house.
- 就快了   - 当然
- Quite soon. - Absolutely.
下午好
Good afternoon.
Aranud 这位怡人的男士是谁
Arnaud, who is this delicious man?
Mercier中校
Colonel Mercier,
Angela Hope女士
Lady Angela Hope.
Roddy Fitzware
Roddy Fitzware.
你不能待在巴黎 中校
You can't live in Paris, Colonel,
不然我要将与你见面当做我的工作了
or I'd have made it my business to meet you.
我受宠若惊 但是目前 我住在华沙
I'm flattered, but at present, I live in Warsaw.
噢  那听起来阴郁又寒冷
Oh? That sounds cold and dull.
嗯 今晚的派对可能会令你精神大振的
Well, a party this evening might lift your spirits.
一位新人艺术家的个人展出
An exhibition of a new artist.
他是一个顽童
He's something of an enfant terrible,
所以今晚必定会以
so the evening is bound to end in
酗酒和暴力为结束
drunkenness and violence.
这很诱人 但我今晚要赶火车
It's tempting, but I'm on a train tonight.
我要到乡下去和我的姐姐过圣诞节
I'm spending Christmas with my sister in the country.
噢  真遗憾
Oh? What a pity.
那么我希望我们明年可以再见
Then I hope we meet again next year.
荣幸之至
A pleasure.
毋须天才的头脑便
It doesn't take a genius to guess
可猜测希特勒先生的意图
Herr Hitler's intentions.
知道他最爱说的一句话么
Know his favourite saying?
世界希望被欺骗
"The world wants to be deceived,
因此让它被欺骗吧
therefore let it be deceived."
并且他没错  读读报纸吧
And he's not wrong. Just read the newspapers.
你有注意听我说的话么
Are you listening to a word I'm saying?
这些话我都听过了 Max
I've heard it all before, Max.
老天啊 这可是圣诞节
For God's sake, it's Christmas.
啊 见着你可真好  还有你 你看上去不错
Ah, good to see you. And you, you look very well.
你的假期怎么样 中校
How was your holiday, Colonel?
非常愉快
Very pleasant.
我和我姐姐待在乡下和巴黎城里
I was with my sister in the country and also Paris.
真羡慕你在巴黎
I envy you Paris.
贵国那边事态如何
How are things in the motherland?
目前尚艰难
Difficult at present.
那些试验
The trials.
我们被召回了
We have been recalled.
也许是升职吧
Promotion, perhaps?
更像是一发子弹
More likely a bullet.
斯大林在清除所有的老布尔什维克党
Stalin is purging all the old Bolsheviks.
你能帮助我们吗
Can you help us?
我们喜欢你 你知道的 中校
We like you, as you know, Colonel.
但我们总觉得
But we always felt...
你在这儿的职责比
that your function here was more...
外交更秘密
clandestine than diplomatic.
并且我们理解你期望着能有所回报
And we understand you would expect something in return.
为了让你离开波兰
For getting you out of Poland?
你们被监视了么  就在这儿
Are you being watched? Here?
我们没法说
We can't say.
他们非常善于隐匿自己不被发现
They're very good at it when they don't want you to know.
我得去贝尔格莱德呆几天
I have to go to Belgrade for a few days.
- 等我回来再说吧   - 别拖太久
- Let's talk when I return. - Don't wait too long.
这趟旅行是Jourdain的主意吗
Was this trip Jourdain's idea?
当然
Of course.
他会尽其所能把你从局里带出来的
He'll do anything to get you out of the office.
这算是一个安慰
But there is one consolation.
一月份去贝尔格莱德?
For Belgrade in January?
这是国际联盟的会议
It's a League of Nations conference.
所以Anna会在场
So Anna will be there.
她甚至有可能在你的火车上
She may even be on your train.
晚餐上你想要
Would you prefer
首席还是次席 Colonel
the first or second seating for dinner, Colonel?
Skarbek小姐选择哪种席位了?
Which seating is Mademoiselle Skarbek down for?
这位女士不在名单内 先生
The lady's not listed, sir.
那么要次席
The second, then.
还要点别的么 先生
You prefer something else, sir?
一杯人头马
Just a Remy Martin.
Anna
Anna!
我在找你  你去哪了
I looked for you. Where were you?
我和一些同事去了克拉科夫
I got on at Krakow with some colleagues.
我还单独进餐  真是浪费
And I dined alone. What a waste.
请坐吧
Please...
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
和你去同一个会议
The same conference as you.
我怀疑它能起到什么好作用
I doubt it will do any good.
还有人听国联的话么
Does anyone listen to the League any more?
尤其现在墨索里尼带着意大利退出了
Especially now Mussolini's pulled Italy out.
你希望知道什么呢
What do you hope to learn?
老实说
To be honest,
在听说你也在那儿之前我也打算请辞这差事的
I intended to bow out till I heard you'd be there.
你脑子里在想什么  一场火车上的罗曼史?
What did you have in mind? An adventure on a train?
不是
No.
更多
More.
我在追求你 Anna
I'm pursuing you, Anna.
你知道我的处境
You know my situation.
是的 我知道
Yes, I do.
这毫无影响
Makes no difference.
我们还几乎不了解对方
We hardly know each other.
你觉着我们到哪儿了
Where do you think we are?
下一站是布达佩斯
The next stop's Budapest.
我宁愿谈谈华沙
I'd rather talk about Warsaw.
我爱上你了 Anna
I'm in love with you, Anna.
我都忘了这种感觉了
I'd forgotten these feelings.
你确定
Are you sure about this?
世事多变
With the way things are in the world,
这是我唯一能确定的事情
it's the only thing I AM sure about.
并且我不相信你是爱Max的
And I don't believe you're in love with Max.
你并不知道我对Max的感情
You have no idea about my feelings for Max!
我曾漂泊不定
I was adrift.
他将我引入这项工作
He pushed me to take this job.
他让我感觉到我是有用的
He made me feel useful...
很有用的人
relevant.
Max是我的锚
Max is my anchor.
现在无法安定的人是我
Then it's me who's adrift.
你必须给我时间
You must give me time.
去结束这一切
To end it my way.
你被监视了 我的朋友
You're under surveillance, my friend.
并不是高等级别的 我们很容易发现他们
Not very high-grade, we spotted them quite easily.
他们
"Them"?
一个四人的队伍 所以他们很谨慎
A team of four, so they are taking it seriously.
一个乌克兰人
One's Ukrainian,
其他三个是德裔波兰人
the other three are Poles, of German extraction.
他们中是不是有一个尖嘴猴腮的
Does one of them have a pinched face,
像一只好斗的黄鼠狼
like a fierce weasel?
你见过他们
You've seen him before?
是啊  Uhl被绑架的那一天
Yeah. The day Uhl was abducted.
就是他  他们在看着呢
That's him. They are watching
不论在公寓里还是出门你都被监视了
your apartment and tailing you when you go out.
我想你知道我和Anna
I suppose you know things are heating up
Skarbek的关系
between Anna Skarbek
正在升温
and me.
我听说了  上星期她不是留宿两次了么
I had heard. Didn't she stay over twice last week?
我想让她搬过来同住
I want her to move in with me.
一个曾经和一个有着可疑声誉的
A woman who was formerly living in
俄罗斯流亡者
sin with a Russian emigre
同居的女人
of dubious reputation?
这足够把你的上司吓得尿裤子了
That should make your superiors piss their pantaloons!
Max很脆弱  你还不懂么
Max is fragile. Can't you understand?
他感觉 无家可归
He feels... displaced.
一无所有
Dispossessed.
一旦我离开了 他就完全孤身一人了
When I leave, he'll be completely alone.
所以你还没有告诉他么
So you still haven't told him?
还没有 我需要拿捏好时间
Not yet, I have to pick my moment.
我们的生活并不像在你床上一样简单
Our lives aren't as simple as they are in your bed.
我们的生活从来不简单
Our lives will never be simple.
是谁
Who is it?
Malka Rozen  求你了中校
Malka Rozen. Please, Colonel,
让我进去
let me in!
噢 老天  他受伤了
Oh, God! He's hurt!
Viktor  我们来这的路上
Viktor. We were on our way here.
他们知道了!
They know!
他在冰上滑倒伤到了脚踝
He fell on the ice and hurt his ankle.
在哪儿
Where?
那个小公园里
In the small park.
教堂边的广场上?
In the square by the church?
是的 对 那有个教堂
Yes, yes, there is a church!
Wlada 带Rozen夫人去厨房
Wlada, take Madame Rozen into the kitchen
泡些茶
and make some tea.
那是谁  发生什么事了
Who is it? What's going on?
出事了  我得走了
There's a problem. I have to go out.
我走后 就把门关好
When I leave, lock the door behind me
别给任何人开门
and don't open it for anyone.
没事了 没事了
It's all right, it's all right,
- Viktor   - 他们知道
- Viktor. - They know,
上校 他们知道了
Colonel.They know.
好了 好了 没事 来吧
All right, all right, all right. Come on.
别担心  我会搞定的
Don't worry. Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
为什么是今晚 Viktor
Why tonight, Viktor?
发生什么事了
What happened?
大使馆临时召开晚间会议
A late meeting was called at the Embassy.
我们的一个朋友
One of our friends...
一个很好的老朋友
a good friend from the old days...
突然不肯跟我们说话了
suddenly wouldn't talk to us.
他都看在眼里
It was in his eyes.
他被审问了 我们能感觉得到
He'd been questioned, we could feel it.
我们知道  我们甚至都没回家取我们的东西
We knew. We didn't even go home to get our things.
好了 继续走吧  没多远了
Right, keep walking. Not far.
你半辈子都在为他们干活
You work half your life for them.
25年的服务 公忠体国
25 years of service, faith and obedience.
到现在你还会
And still you're afraid of
害怕半夜的敲门声
the knock on the door at midnight.
怎么停下了
Why have we stopped?
他是谁 Vicktor
Who was he, Viktor?
我不知道
I wouldn't know.
Anna 是我
Anna, it's me.
Viktor  你还好吗
Viktor! Are you all right?
他冻僵了  Wlada 烧热水
He's frozen. Wlada, run a hot bath.
有多热就多热  再拿些干衣服来
As hot as you can get it. And some dry clothes.
我能做什么  我能帮什么忙吗
What can I do? Can I help?
你现在必须回家 Anna
You must go home now, Anna.
你什么都没看见
And you saw none of this.
看在老天的面上 带他们到大使馆
For God's sake, bring them to the Embassy!
冒着跟苏联政府发生外交冲突的危险吗
Risk a diplomatic confrontation with the Soviets?
巴黎方面会想解决这个的
Paris will want to handle this.
巴黎能足够快地搞定他们
Paris will get them soon enough.
找架私人飞机带他们到那
Find a private plane to get them there.
我们必须把这事揽自己身上
We have to keep this to ourselves.
我们不能冒让波兰人尴尬的危险
We can't risk embarrassing the Poles.
你不应该自己一个人管这事的
You shouldn't be running this alone.
他们为我而来  他们信任我
They came to me. They trust me.
你的伯爵夫人也信任你
So did your Countess.
- 你带了几个人   - 两个
- How many are with you? - Two.
一个安排在后街 一个安排在
Put one in the back alley, one on
楼梯上 你守前门  带家伙了吗
the stairs and you out front. Do you have a weapon?
好极了  行动吧
Good. Don't hesitate.
我们在等谁  我们的德国朋友吗
Who are we expecting? Our German friends?
不是的 是俄国人  苏联内务人民委员会的
No, these are Russians. NKVD.
那敢情好啊
Oh. It will be a pleasure.
我们和法国之间没有什么
We had little to do with France.
我们行动集中在波兰人身上
Our operations were centred on the Poles.
尤其是对社会党的渗透上
Especially penetration of the socialist parties.
莫斯科总部看中这个
Moscow Central is obsessed with this.
我们做的与他人无异
We did what everyone does.
作战计划 武器生产 政治诽谤
War plans, arms production, political personalities,
边境防御
border defences.
我觉得这和你的工作差远了 中校
I doubt it's much different from what you do, Colonel.
德国的情报网呢
Any German networks?
我们还没掌握他们
We didn't handle them.
那是保护区的中坚力量
That was the preserve of the elite.
不是你吗
Not you?
这些日子搞情报的犹太人不那么吃香
The Jews in the service aren't so favoured these days.
没德国的情报么?  你确定?
No German information? You're sure?
只有流言
Only gossip.
比如
Such as?
一个集中营
A camp,
他们在波美拉尼亚培养波兰的间谍
in Pomerania where they train spies to work in Poland.
- 当然你早知道了   - 我当然知道
- Surely you know already. - Of course I know!
如果要我说服巴黎挽救你们的老命
If I'm to convince Paris to save your skins,
我需要的情报可不止这点
I need more than this.
你对IN6了解有多少
What do you know about IN6?
IN6  是Kovak在经营的吗
IN6? Was that Kovak's operation?
不 不是Kovak  是Morozov
No, it wasn't Kovak... it was Morozov.
她说的没错 是Morozov
She's right, it was Morozov.
那是什么
What was it?
他在IN6里有线人
He had a contact who worked in the IN6 office.
某个帮他向黑色阵线隐瞒他的
Someone who had concealed his
- 政治背景的人   - 他们
- political affiliation to the Black Front. - They were...
我知道  希特勒在纳粹党内的反对者
I know. Hitler's opponents in the Nazi Party.
左翼势力
The left wing.
继续
Go on.
这个人受胁迫成为苏联的间谍
This man was pressured to become a Soviet agent.
威胁奏效了一段时间 然后
It worked for a while, then...
Morozov被肃清了 于是行动就停止了
Morozov was purged, so the operation stalled.
于是这个人
And this man
继续在德国情报机构的核心工作
still works in the heart of German intelligence?
是的  他并不是希特勒那边的人
Yes. And he is no friend of Hitler.
叫什么
A name?
我需要一个名字
I need a name.
那只是个代号
It was a code name.
一 一种鸟  我想是种鸟的名字
A...A bird. I think it was a bird.
Kanarejka  还是什么
Kanarejka? Something like that?
- 不 不是的   - 那是什么
- No, it wasn't. - Well, what then?
是种海鸟 亲爱的
It was a seabird, dear.
在海港随处可见
In harbours everywhere.
"Chaika" 就是这个
"Chaika," That was it!
海鸥
Seagull.
她是不是很厉害啊
Isn't she something?
你打算和Rozens夫妇一起飞往巴黎吗
So you intend to fly to Paris with the Rozens?
- 是的   - 真的有必要吗
- I do, yes. - Is that really necessary?
我们必须继续追查这情报
We have to follow up on this information.
这可是希特勒在他自己党内的敌人
This is opposition to Hitler inside his own party.
如果我们能挖掘到它 那可是无价之宝
If we can tap into that, it could be invaluable.
当Rozen夫人到你公寓的时候
Hmm. When Madame Rozen came to your apartment,
你不是一个人吧
you weren't alone?
不是  我的女仆在  还有一位年轻女士
No. My maid was there. And also a young lady.
Anna Skarbek
Anna Skarbek. Yes.
是的  我们当时在一起吃晚餐
We'd been to dinner.
当时是凌晨一点以后了
This was after one in the morning,
所以可以假设你们不止是共进晚餐
so presumably you'd had more than dinner.
这关你什么事
Is that any of your business?
大使认为这关我的事
The Ambassador thinks it is.
因为你现在严重受到牵连了
Because you're now seriously compromised.
这女人可是Maxim Mostov的情人
The woman is Maxim Mostov's mistress.
这段关系早就结束了
That relationship is at an end.
她很有可能不仅只是个
It's possible she's more than
倒霉的情人而是个心甘情愿的共犯
a hapless mistress but a willing accomplice.
真是扯淡
That's ridiculous!
大使强烈认为
The Ambassador feels very strongly
在这样的环境下
in the circumstances
最好是断了这份关系
it would be best to terminate this liaison.
我可没打算这么做
I'm not prepared to do that.
或许你应该仔细地考虑一下
Perhaps you should think very carefully about that.
Rozen夫妇叛变了 是吧
The Rozens were defecting, presumably?
你知道我不能对此发表评论
You know I can't comment on that.
Max非常确定是这样
Max feels certain that's it.
你和他讨论过了?
You discussed it with him?
他听说的  谁没听说呢
He's heard about it. Who hasn't?
Anna 现在的形势非常棘手
Anna, this is a very tricky situation.
大使不希望我再跟你见面
The Embassy doesn't want me to see you any more.
为什么  因为他们认为我是个间谍吗
Why? Cos they think I'm a spy?
还是个荡妇
Or a slut?
如果他们坚持 我就辞职
If they insist, I'll resign.
我得离开一阵子
I have to go away for a few days.
等我回来的时候
By the time I get back,
我希望你和Max真的了断了
I want it all over between you and Max.
我不喜欢最后通牒
I don't like ultimatums.
我希望你能自由
I need you to be free.
把头低下
Keep your heads down.
继续
Go on!
他看起来很火大
He seems upset.
换做是你呢
Wouldn't you be?
喂  什么啊
Hey! What?!
我不介意你和他搞上几次
I don't mind if you screw him a few times
摆脱你的组织
and get it out of your system.
不是这样的
It's not like that.
我知道他的魅力所在  战争英雄
I can see the attraction. The war hero.
20年前杀害了我无数同胞
Killed lots of my countrymen 20 years ago.
他穿起制服很帅气 甚至
And he looks good in a uniform, even if
他走起路来都像屁股上有根拨火棍似的
he walks like he has a poker up his arse.
Max 别这样
Max, don't do this.
好吧 我早就知道会有这一天
Well, I suppose I knew this would happen one day.
你还年轻 你还有活力
You are young, you are alive.
我只是个悲哀的
I'm just a sad,
卑鄙的老混蛋
miserable old bastard.
当我们一起去聚会的时候
I see it in people's faces
我从人们的脸上看得出来
when we go to parties.
"她是怎么看上他的"
"What dose she see in him?"
Max 你是个好人
Max, you're a wonderful man
是我自己选择和你在一起的
and I chose to be with you.
现在你选择离开
And now you choose to go.
我出去了  我回来的时候你最好已经走了
I'm going out. Just be gone when I get back.
而且我可没藏着见鬼的伏特加
And don't hide the goddamn vodka!
你认为Rozen夫妇告诉你的事
Do you think there's any value
究竟有没有价值
in what the Rozens told you...
或是那只是为了保全性命杜撰出来的
or is it just some fiction to save their skins?
我相信他们  我想继续追查
I believe them. I want to follow up on it.
那就得等我们自己
That'll have to wait
着手调查他们了
until we've had a go at them ourselves.
我急着赶回华沙
I'm anxious to get back to Warsaw as soon as possible.
这座城市貌似对你有很大的吸引力
The city seems to have attractions for you.
当然这不是我们当初派你到那时的态度
Certainly not your attitude when we posted you there.
我肯定我待在那准没错
I believe it's the right place for me...
此时此刻
and the right time.
我同意
And I agree.
你能很好地解决这事儿的
And you handled this whole episode most commendably,
中校
Colonel.
享受你的咖啡吧
I'll leave you to your coffee.
他为什么不喜欢你
Why doesn't he like you?
他讨厌戴高乐 也知道我为他效力
He hates de Gaulle and knows I served with him.
他怀念战争 那是他的问题
He missed the war, that's his problem.
想到你那些勋章就受不了
Can't bear the thought of all your medals.
上一次你来这的时候 提到一位Lapp博士
Last time you were here, you mentioned a Dr Lapp.
你的直觉是正确的
Your instincts were right.
这位好博士
The good doctor is
在德国的军事情报部门
in the German military intelligence.
他和Admiral Canaris和他那
He and Admiral Canaris and
Canaris 纳粹德国军事情报局局长
反谍报部门都讨厌盖世太保
his Abwehr loathe the SD
和希特勒 所有的下流勾当
and Hitler, the whole nasty business.
政治斗争和社会斗争不分轩轾
It's as much social as political.
他们视自己为绅士
They see themselves as gentlemen,
视纳粹为恶棍
the Nazis as gangsters.
那么他会有用
Then he could be useful.
来了
All right.
All right!
我来了
I'm coming!
那是谁
Who's that?
Klaus和Frida身无长物地
Klaus and Frida fled from Frankfurt
逃离了法兰克福
with only the clothes on their backs.
他们有给政府带来威胁吗
Do they pose a threat to the government?
他们是大提琴手 看在上帝的面上
They're CELLISTS, for God's sake.
根据现在德国的法律
By German law now, persons of
超过25%非雅利安血统的人禁止演出
more than 25% non-Aryan blood are forbidden to play
贝多芬 莫扎特还有巴赫的音乐
Beethoven, Mozart and Bach.
把他们留给格什温吧
Leaves them Gershwin, I suppose.
美国著名作曲家
温莎公爵究竟为什么
What on earth was the Duke of Windsor
要拜访希特勒
doing visiting Hitler?
也许是Simpson夫人的主意
Probably Mrs Simpson's idea,
他总是照她说的做
he always does what she says.
她是怎么拴住他的
What sort of hold does she have over him?
我想象她一掌拍得他想起他的奶娘
I imagine she spanks him and reminds him of his nanny!
这是非常英国的事
That's a very English thing.
您华沙的电话终于来了 中校
Your call to Warsaw at last, Colonel.
恕我失陪
Do excuse me.
别太久哦
Don't be too long.
喂
Hello?
Anna 你到哪去了
Anna, where were you?
我一整天都在找你
I've been trying to reach you all day.
- 怎么了   - 他们带走了Max
- What's the matter? - They took Max!
他们像带走一个罪犯一样
They just took him in the night
在晚上带走了他
like a common criminal!
等等 你在说什么 谁带走了Max
Wait, what are you saying? Who took Max?
你知道是谁带走了他 看在上帝的面上
You know who took him, for God's sake!
我去拜访了你的朋友Pakulski
I went to visit your friend Pakulski.
他说波兰人对他的签证毫无异议
He said the Poles had no problem with his visa,
是法国人想让他滚的
it was the French that wanted him out.
你就不能像我说的那样 由我来解决这些问题
You couldn't wait for me to deal with it like I asked!
Anna 你这样无济于事
Anna, you're not making sense.
他们甚至不让我见他
They won't even let me see him!
他们要把他遣送回莫斯科
They're sending him back to Moscow.
这 这简直是判他死刑
It's... it's a death sentence!
Anna  Anna 喂
Anna? Anna, hello?
Mercier中校表示他很遗憾
Colonel Mercier sends his regrets,
但是他必须得离开了
but he was obliged to leave.
国家大事么 将军?
Affairs of state, General?
- 也可能是心事哦   - 怎么说
- Or the heart, perhaps. - Why would you say that?
目前为止我见过他两次
Well, I've met him twice now
两次他都没表现出
and on both occasions he's shown
想要和我春风一度的意思
not the slightest inclination to take me to bed.
你得明白 大使没得选择
You must realise, the Ambassador had no choice!
你受到牵连 这势在必行
You were compromised, it was imperative.
这是报复
It was vindictive,
你没必要这么窝囊地
unnecessary and cowardly of you
等我离开才下手
to wait until after I left.
我们现在有别的优先事务
We have other priorities now.
你从Rozen夫妇那盘问到什么情报吗
What did you learn from the Rozen debriefing?
我已经得到授权管理此事了
I have leads I've been authorised to act upon.
他们是干什么的
What are they?
就像我说的 我已经得到授权了
Like I said, I have been authorised.
巴黎方面觉得知道的人越少越好
Paris feels the fewer people in the know, the better.
如果她想消失一会儿 就让她去呗
If she wants to disappear for a while, so be it.
我得和她谈谈
I need to talk to her.
我需要一个解释的机会
I need a chance to explain.
她充满了歉疚和愤怒
She's filled with guilt and anger.
因为如果她没和你相爱的话
Because what happened to Max would
这事就不会发生在Max身上
not have happened if she had not fallen in love.
她对你关上了心门
Her heart is closed to you.
我的建议么  等待时机吧
My advice? Bide your time.
我们还有多少时间
How much time do any of us have?
希特勒随时会进军奥地利
Hitler will march into Austria any minute.
他不会在那停留的
And he won't stop there.
所以我们必须想方设法战斗
So we must fight any way we can.
Askenazy
Askenazy.
波兰最伟大的历史学家之一
One of Poland's great historians.
请坐
Please.
我们能在这私聊吗
Can we talk privately here?
可以  这就是为什么我提议这样
Yes. That's why I suggested it.
这是属于一位朋友的
It belongs to a friend,
而且没人会在一天的这个时候来
and no-one comes here at this time of day.
在进入谈话之前 你得给我
On the occasions when we talked, you gave me
相信你不是你们国家的领导人的朋友
reason to believe you're no friend
的理由
to your country's leaders.
我也知道你是反间谍机关的成员
I also know you're a member of the Abwehr.
据我所知
As I know that
你跟Deuxieme Bureau
you are connected to the Deuxieme Bureau
和Beauvilliers将军有所联系
and General Beauvilliers.
真想知道我们这个秘密的世界
Surprising how few secrets
还剩多少秘密
there are in our secret world.
你不曾是黑色前线的成员吗
Were you ever a member of the Black Front?
没有  我从没加入过纳粹组织
No. I never joined Nazi organisations,
没有任何污点
of whatever shade.
但他们中也有
But they were amongst
希特勒最坚定的敌人
Hitler's most determined enemies.
是的 这就是为什么
Yes, that's why
那些没有死的人
the ones that aren't dead
躲起来或流亡了
are either in hiding or exile.
我听说一名前成员
I have been told a former member
仍作为IN6的核心在工作
still works at the heart of IN6.
放桌上就好了 年轻人
Just leave them on the table, young man.
这儿有个人或许能帮你
There is a man who might help you.
他曾是古代语言的教授
He was once a professor of ancient languages.
现在他躲在
Now he's in hiding in
捷克斯洛伐克 因为受到盖世太保的追捕
Czechoslovakia because he's hunted by the Gestapo.
你应该迅速动身
You should move quickly.
他还写反纳粹的小册子
He still writes anti-Nazi
偷运进德国呢
pamphlets that are smuggled into Germany,
这激怒了他们
which infuriates them.
所以我担心他可能不久于世了
So I fear he may not be long for this world.
我已经越界了 中校
I'm crossing a line here, Colonel.
如果我给你他的名字 你必须得向我保证
If I give you his name, you must make me a promise.
你向他提供资金但你
You may offer him money but you
不能吓着他 因为我们还跟他有联系
may not threaten him, because we still talk to him.
所以别伤害他  同意吗
So do not bruise him. Agreed?
同意
Agreed.
派件员在早上的派件后回来
The courier goes back on the morning express,
所以现在快看  然后签字
so look through this now. And you have to sign for it.
数一下吧 务必
Count it, by all means.
这里有Beauvilliers将军的消息
And there's a message from General Beauvilliers.
"请千万不要被抓住"
"Please do try very hard not to get caught.
"最好避免到赌场去"
"And best to avoid a visit to the casino."
我要外出至少一个星期 Wlada
I'll be away for at least a week, Wlada.
休假吧 见见你的家人
Take some time off, see your family.
去车站的路上我想停一下
I want to make a stop on the way to the station.
盯着他
Book him.
安息吧 伯爵夫人
Rest in peace, Countess.
Marek  怎么了
Marek? What happened?
他在跟踪你  于是我跟着他
He was following you. So I followed him.
然后他发现了我 准备对我开枪
Then he saw me and aimed his pistol.
于是我开枪杀了他
So I shot him.
我们得走了 头儿
We should go, boss.
我们究竟该怎么处理这尸体
What the hell do we do with the body?!
死得真是地方  我们只差一把铁铲了
Good place to die. If only we had a shovel.
好了  你去开车  我来处理这个
OK. You take the car... and I'll take care of this.
跟我们走
干的漂亮